REGINA GALIEVA

rg-galieva.com github.com/rg-galieva linkedin.com/in/rg-galieva

Experienced full stack engineer, 9+ years in tech. Worked with projects of varying complexity both as an engineer and a team lead. Right now focused on front-end development. Passionate about sophisticated single page apps. In love with Javascript. Have strong skill in responsive layouts. The more challenging features - the better!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: React, MobX, Redux, Typescript, Antd UI, Semantic UI

Back-end: Node, Express, Swagger, Postgres, Mongo

Styles: Sass, Less, PostCss, Css-modules, BEM

Unit-tests: Mocha, Jest **Version Control:** Git, Svn

Dev Tools: Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Babel, ESLint

Dev Deploy: Heroku, Amazon S3, Jenkins **Familiar with:** JAVA EE (Spring, Tapestry),

Ruby (RoR), PHP (Wordpress)

Dev Methodology: Agile (Scrum + Kanban)

EXPERIENCE

[PRESENCE] - Senior Front End Engineer / Project Lead

Software development agency focused on web, mobile, VR, AR

SF Bay Area, CA Contract, Sep 2018- present

- Developed a client portal for investment company from scratch (set up ui infrastructure and tech stack)
- Feature owner (front end): authentication and user roles, dynamic routing with progressive enhancement, custom layouts for private and public routes, dynamic custom area/pie/bar charts
- Tech stack: React, Redux, Recharts, Webpack

[FR8STAR] - Senior Front End Engineer

Load board, freight matching, and bidding marketplace

SF Bay Area, CA May 2017- August 2018

- Feature owner (front-end): request-for-quote flow (entry point for shippers), rate calculator for shippers, load matcher (entry point for carriers), shipper registration, rate calculator widget for partners
- Worked on API-designs, global UI-acrhitecture, reusable responsive components library, style guides, performance optimization, 3rd-party API integration
- Tech stack: React, MobX, google maps API, Node, Swagger

[ADLUXE] - UI Team Lead

Creative technologies, Rich Media and Video Advertising Production

Moscow, RU

2015-2017

- Led the development of 10+ of company products
- Successfully implemented Agile methodology in a distributed, multi-timezone team
- Moved company website from PHP to React single page app, guided team in the development of SPA
- Guided team in the development of SPA
- Created an educational tech program for managers and designers (dev fundamentals, js, git, webpack, jenkins)

[MAIL.RU GROUP] - Front End Developer

The leading Russian Internet company with 100M+ users

Moscow, RU 2013-2015

- Led UI development (code style, code structure, style guides)
- Cross platform development for desktop, mobile, in-game (awesomium) from scratch
- Released 3 global redesigns of the product. Implemented company style guide.

[IFREE / SIMAI] - Web Developer

Mobile App development & distribution companies

Saint-Petersburg / Ufa, RU

2008-2013

- Launched 20+ sites, landings, email newsletters, promo pages (PHP), admin applications (Ruby on Rails)
- Java EE: Web applications (front end, back end) using Spring MVC (Maven, JPA, JSP).

EDUCATION

UFA STATE AVIATION TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Master's degree in telecommunication systems

Ufa, RU 2005-2010

Saint-Petersburg, RU

I-FREE TECHNICAL ACADEMY

- Was among TOP 20% of chosen to participate in the Academy

2013

- Took the 1st place among 10 projects.

GRAPHIC DESIGN BOOTCAMP

Moscow, RU

10 weeks course: graphic design in web. Effective designs principles, theory and practice

2015